從前...
Once upon a time...
有一個孤獨的國王
There was a lonely king.
他不分晝夜的
He spent many days and many nights
流浪著  尋找著
Wandering   searching
尋找那個獨一無二的人
Looking for that one special someone.
晚安
Good night.
晚安  Jody
Good night   Jody.
晚安  Clemons太太
Good night   Mrs. Clemons.
那樣一個
That...One...
完美的...女人
Perfect...Woman
誰將成為他的王后呢
Who would be his queen.
爸爸
Daddy!
我一直等你來看我
I was hoping you'd come tonight.
能再給我講個故事嗎
Can you tell me another story?
這個
Well...
只要你乖乖躺著
If you lay back down there
閉上你的小眼睛
And close your little eyes.
閉上眼睛
Close your eyes.
孤獨的國王向更遙遠的地方進發
And the lonely king searched far and wide
尋找那個會成為他王后的女人
Looking for this woman who would be his queen.
新墨西哥州  科林斯角
就在他即將絕望的時候
He had almost given up hope of ever finding her
他來到一個小酒館
When he came upon this small tavern...
看到了一個普通的鄉村女侍者
With a simple country barmaid.
這時  她看了孤獨的國王一眼
Now   when she looked at the lonely king
國王覺得他們好像已經相知相識
He felt as if they had known each other
千年之久
For a thousand years.
你需要添些酒嗎
Do you need a refill?
Tanya  我估計我要自己回家了
Tanya   I guess I'm going home alone.
失陪一下
Excuse me a second.
首先  你不是一個人
First of all   you're not alone.
第二  你不能開車了
And secondly   you're not driving.
鑰匙拿來
Keys.
Betty  給Sam叫輛出租車
Betty   Sam needs a cab.
好的
Sure.
真奇怪
That's weird.
你看到那位老兄去哪了嗎
Did you see where that guy went?
他在等待時機
So he waited
直到她獨自一個人的時候
Until she was alone
從遠處靜靜的望著她
Watching from afar
因為國王害怕和她說話
Because he was afraid to speak to her.
直到有一天
And then one day...
她的馬車壞了
Her carriage wouldn't start.
國王心想
And the king thought...
這是命運的安排
This is fate.
所以他單騎下山去營救她
And so he rode down to rescue her.
她對國王說
And she said to him...
都怪這大雨
Must be the rain.
打開引擎蓋
Pop the hood.
謝謝
Thank you!
國王把她救了嗎  爸爸
Did he rescue her   daddy?
她是國王的真命天女嗎
Was she the one?
國王是這麼想的
Well   the king thought so.
現在試試
Try it now!
好了
Yes...
嗨  我非常感激
Hey   I appreciate your--
嗨
Hello?
人呢
你還好嗎
You ok?
然後他們一起騎著駿馬消失在黑夜中
So they rode off into the night together.
最後他們在一起了嗎
And they lived happily ever after?
沒有  寶貝
Well   no   sweet pea.
她不是國王要找的人
She wasn't the one.
不過別擔心
But don't worry.
國王永遠不會停止追尋
The king's never gonna stop looking.
如果他永遠也找不到王后怎麼辦呢
What if he never finds a queen?
這樣的話  他就會
Well   then he'll just--
我們就會去一個更好的地方
We'll just go to a better place.
晚安  公主
Good night   princess.
她名叫Tanya Hill  29歲  是一個酒館的侍者
Her name was Tanya Hill. She was 29   a bartender.
兩天前在新墨西哥州的艾吉伍德被發現
Found 2 days ago in Edgewood   New Mexico.
她是6個月內的第五名受害女子
She's the fifth woman in over 6 months
被棄屍在40號和25號州際公路旁的溝渠中
To be found dead in a ditch off the I-40 and I-25.
被兇手徒手勒死  沒有性侵犯跡象
All were manually strangled. None were sexually assaulted.
也許勒死受害人能使他獲得心理滿足
Well   maybe the act of strangulation is what gets him off.
她們在哪堻Q劫持的
Where were they abducted from?
哪堻ㄕ
All over.
他們不僅僅跨越了州界
Well   they're not just crossing state lines.
案發的城市彼此間更是相距數百英里
These cities are hundreds of miles apart.
死了這麼多人  我們為何才接到協助請求呢
That's a lot of bodies. Why is it taking so long to be invited?
還沒有協助請求  我們從公路連環殺手數據庫瞭解到這個情況
We haven't been invited. We found this on HSK database.
很多地方警局都不希望惹上這個麻煩
Well   a lot of police departments won't want this problem.
地理側寫顯示只有一個地方有麻煩
The geographic profile shows that only one of them has it.
他們只是還沒意識到
They just don't know it yet.
-你怎麼知道  -因為他有一個慣性活動區域
- How do you know that? - Because he has a comfort zone
取決於他前往拋屍地點的方向
Based on the direction he was heading when he dumped the bodies.
全部5個案件說明這個不明嫌犯
All 5 cases point to our unsub
前往的地方是新墨西哥州的艾吉伍德
Heading to edgewood   new mexico.
也是我們要去的地方
Now so are we.
你搭車來的
You got a ride.
你好
Hi!
不好意思
Oh. Excuse me.
你把這個落在桌子上了
I think you forgot these.
嘻嘻
Hee hee!
你好可愛啊
You are so cute.
拜
Bye!
拜拜
Goodbye.
你知不知道誰往西邊走
Do you know anyone that's heading west?
真抱歉
Hmm. Sorry.
我去
I am.
太好了
Great.
犯罪心理  第5季第17集
Criminal Minds S05E17
劇作家田納西·威廉姆斯曾說
Tennessee Williams said
我們所有人都在自己的軀殼內
"We're all of us sentenced to solitary confinement
被孤獨的囚禁終生
Inside our own skins   for life."
很明顯這個不明嫌犯不在乎受害人被發現
Clearly this unsub doesn't care about his victims being found.
或者說他覺得通過受害人無法查到他
Or he knows he can't be linked to them.
法醫鑒定報告支撐了這個觀點
The M.E.'s report supports that.
5個受害人身上發現同一組DNA
Matching DNA was found on all 5 victims.
-但是在數據庫堿d不到人  -是的
- But not in any database. - Right.
受害人特徵和劫持地點都很有規律
It's also in keeping with the victimology and abduction sites.
什麼規律
Which are what?
富人區和善待罪犯的區域
Target rich and offender friendly.
不同被劫持者的死亡時間
Time of death from time of abduction
有很顯著的不同
Varies dramatically in each case.
一些人12小時後被害  一些則是24小時後
Some lived 12 hours   others 24 before they were killed.
那麼他劫持他們幹什麼呢
So what's he doing with them?
他不與她們發生性行為
Well   he's not having sex with them.
沒有折磨甚至被捆綁的跡象
There's no sign of torture or even restraints.
DNA來自身體的什麼部位
What was the matching DNA?
皮膚  在5個受害人的指甲
Uh   skin. That and metal shavings were found
殘留著一些皮膚碎屑和金屬粉末
Under the fingernails of all 5 victims.
Tanya只剩下一個手指蓋
Tanya only had one nail left.
一個手指蓋嗎
One nail?
恩  看起來無論被關在哪
Yeah. It looks like whatever she was in
她一直想方設法的逃出來
She tried to claw her way out.
JJ  讓Garcia將受害人類型和劫持地點
JJ   have Garcia match victimology
與公路連環殺手數據庫中一年內的數據進行比對
And abduction sites to hsk findings for the last year.
如果他繼續按照這個時間表作案
If he sticks to this timeline
艾吉伍德很快就會再發現一具屍體
Edgewood is about to discover another body.
她在此向西32.9英里的地方被劫持
So she was abducted 32.9 miles west of here
也就是說  如果他們沒有超速行駛的話
Which means if they drove the speed limit
他們最多只花30分鐘就到這
They got here in 30 minutes or less.
那麼  要走到那個水溝
So   how long's it gonna take you
需要花多少時間呢
to get in that ditch?
你是叫我去嗎
Get in that ditch?
我膝蓋中過槍  還記得吧
I got shot in the knee   remember?
醫生說我不可以作任何攀爬
My doctor said I'm not allowed to do any climbing.
只是個水溝而已
It's a ditch.
怕弄髒新靴子  是吧
New boots   huh?
是意大利皮革嗎
Italian leather?
沒錯  我也沒轍
Yeah   what can I tell you?
那麼
So   uh
任何路過的汽車都能看到我
from here I can be seen by any passing vehicle.
但是看不到我
And I can't.
她在晚上被拋屍
So she was dumped at night.
肯定沒錯
Must have.
他開車過來
He drives up
扔了屍體
Dumps the body.
完工  離開
Job done   he leaves.
我不這麼認為
I don't think so.
什麼
What?
5位受害者被發現的時候都是像胎兒一樣蜷縮著
All 5 victims were found posed in the fetal position
右手手心朝上  左手手心朝下
With their right arm palm-up   left arm palm-down.
兇手在懺悔嗎
Remorse?
或者在佈置
Or staging.
佈置成什麼
To look like what?
讓她們看起來像在睡覺
Like they're asleep.
你知道原因嗎
You have any ideas why?
不知道
No.
我想  凡事都有第一次
Well   I guess there is a first time for everything.
Rossi  你得把我
Hey   Rossi   I'm gonna need a little bit of help
弄上去
getting out of this ditch.
Rossi
Rossi!
Rossi?
喂
Hey--
算了  還是靠自己
I got it.
我很感激你們的到來
Listen   I appreciate you guys coming down here
但是我只有一具屍體
but I only got one body.
我們認為那是連環殺手干的
Which we believe is the work of a serial killer.
連環案件不應該只有一具屍體吧
Doesn't it have to be more than one to be a series?
如果你把比艾吉伍德稍大一點的範圍也算上的話
If you include a slightly larger area than just Edgewood
我們有5具屍體
We've got 5 bodies.
都是被勒死的  都被擺好姿勢  都被拋屍
All strangled   all staged   and all dumped.
為什麼是艾吉伍德
Why Edgewood?
因為此地對他意義非凡
It's significant to him.
我們認為他要麼在這堛齯j  要麼現在住在這
We believe that he either grew up here or he lives here now.
聽著  我很遺憾有人開車經過我的鎮子
Look   I'm sorry that somebody's driving through my town
並且拋屍  但是這不代表他就在這
and dumping bodies   but it doesn't mean he lives here.
我們正在HSK數據庫
We're searching for more victims
搜尋更多的受害者
through the HSK database.
那是什麼
What's that?
公路連環殺手數據庫
Highway Serial Killer database.
我們幾年前就開始
We started it a few years ago
追蹤全國主要高速公路附近
to track bodies found off of major highways
被發現的屍體
all over the country.
一旦法律實施   不管城鎮多小
Law enforcement   no matter how small the town
執法部門都會上報謀殺案件
reports the murders and
然後我們利用數據庫把他們關聯起來
we use the database to try to connect them.
不管是誰在殘害這些女性  他都不會停下來
Whoever's killing these women isn't slowing down
而且他很快又將把屍體扔在你家門口
and he's about to dump another body on your doorstep.
我的天
Oh   God.
我的天啊
Oh   my God.
住手  住手  你想怎樣
Stop! Stop! What do you want?!
我什麼都會做  告訴我你想幹什麼
I'll do anything. Just tell me what you want!
我想你安靜點
I want you to be quiet.
好  好的  我不說話
OK   ok   I'll stop.
還有呢
What else?
你還想幹什麼
What else do you want?
聊天
To talk.
好  我們聊天
OK   we can talk.
我們可以聊天  我想聊天
We can talk. I want to talk.
我想聊
I want to do that.
不
No...
這是另一個受害者的資料
Here's an M.E. File of another victim.
我們知道所有這些女性
We know that all these women
都是被同一個不明嫌犯勒死的
were strangled by the same unsub.
根據DNA找到了一些證據
There's evidence found by DNA
她們的指甲埵釭鷵搛H片
and metal fragments under their fingernails
但是有其他發現
but there's something else.
Tanya的衣服上沾有柴油
Tanya had diesel fuel on her clothing.
她是在高速路旁被發現的
Well   she was found off the freeway.
我想她們都沾有柴油
I'm sure they all had.
沒錯  還有糖
They all did. And sugar.
幾乎所有受害者衣服上都找到了食用糖
Table sugar was found on almost all the victims' clothing.
糖
Sugar?
糖能吸收柴油
It absorbs diesel fuel.
這是卡車司機的把戲
It's a trucker trick.
我們知道他是如何轉移她們的了
We know how he's transporting them.
我很渴
I'm thirsty.
求你了  我想喝水
Please   I need a drink.
我有問題要先問你
I have some questions first.
什麼都行
Anything.
你想知道什麼
What do you want to know?
這很重要
Well   it's important...
你要仔細聽  這點很重要
It's important that you listen.
明白嗎
Are we clear?
好的
OK.
你信教嗎
Are you religious?
什麼  你說什麼
What? I'm sorry?
你相信上帝嗎
Do you believe in God?
是的
Yeah.
你想要孩子嗎
Do you want children?
也許
Someday...
以後會
maybe.
是的  我想要孩子
Yeah   I do.
我想要  我想要孩子
I do. I really want kids.
我不相信
I don't believe you do.
別
No--
讓我出去
let me out of here!
Courtney  這不代表他不會邀請你去舞會
Courtney   it doesn't mean he won't invite you to the prom.
說真的  媽媽  你不會明白的
Seriously   mom   you just wouldn't understand.
你要知道我以前也上過高中
You know   I did go to high school at one time.
沒錯  好像是50年前的事了
Yeah   like 50 years ago.
我都不知道我為什麼要跟你聊這個
I don't even know why I'm talking to you about this.
我就當沒聽到
I'm just gonna let that one go.
謝天謝地
Thank goodness.
好的
Yeah   ok.
Courtney
Courtney?
Courtney  是你嗎
Courtney   is that you?
你能別晃來晃去的嗎
Hey   will you stop fooling around.
不
Aah! No!
好的
All right.
好的  謝謝  寶貝兒
All right   thanks   baby girl.
Garcia說  有782個卡車司機
Garcia says there's 782 truckers
在這個縣工作和居住
Working and living in this county.
我們需要精簡到具體的路段
We gotta narrow down the specific routes.
那還不夠
We'll need more than that.
小女孩證明
The daughter confirmed.
疑犯是開一輛大型越野車
Definitely driving a big rig.
不過她認不出標誌或者車牌
Now   she wasn't able to make out any logos or see the plate.
我想跟她談談
I'd like to talk to her.
進出縣的每條道路我都設置了檢查站
I got checkpoints at every route in and out of the county.
他一上路  就能發現他
If he's on the road   we'll find him.
他不會在休息站作案
He doesn't hunt at rest stops.
他剛這麼做了
He just did.
這堣蚢L偏僻
It's way too isolated here.
但是個絕佳綁架地點
It's a perfect place to take somebody.
對他來說不是  他喜歡罪犯友好環境
Not for this guy. He goes to offender friendly environments
便於融入  跟受害者交流
So he can blend in and still interact with his victims.
這堮琤豪S法做到
He hasn't had a chance to do that.
如果他是本地人  何必去休息站
Well   if he's from here   why would he need a rest stop?
或許為了銷毀證據
Clean up   maybe.
查過洗手間了嗎
You check the rest rooms yet?
查了  男廁的廁盆都是大便
Yeah   the sink is full of dirt in the men's room.
這是拋屍地點
This is a dump site.
不是綁架地點
It's not an abduction site.
他肯定在附近拋了屍
He must have dumped a body around here somewhere.
警長  請叫你的手下分頭找
Sheriff   I want you to have your officers spread out.
讓他們從溝渠找起
Tell them to start with the ditches.
有什麼特徵嗎  什麼都行
Any distinguishing marks? Anything at all?
我當時沒注意看
I wasn't looking.
在發短信
I was texting.
只聽到有輛卡車發動
I heard a truck start.
我進到廁所時  她已經不見了
When I went to the bathroom   she was gone.
你們能找到她嗎
How are you gonna find her?
疑犯很可能會留在本地
There's a good chance he's gonna stay here.
他為什麼不逃跑
Why wouldn't he just run?
他每次都會回到埃奇伍德
Because he always comes back to edgewood.
你媽媽是第一個他在本地綁架的女子
Your mother is the first woman he's taken from here.
我們只是開車路過
We were just driving through.
我們住在鳳凰城
We live in phoenix.
媽媽只是載我回家
Mom was just trying to get me home
我才能趕上選拔賽
So I could go to tryouts.
你們一定要找到她  她是我唯一的親人
You have to find her. She's all I have.
你應該去警察局
You should come down to the station.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你在哪
Hey   where are you?
我在南邊的樹林
I'm in the woods south of you.
你過來看看
You need to see this.
勒死  指甲縫有金屬屑
Strangled   metal shavings under her nails.
疑犯拋屍後
He dumps her body
在休息站清理
He cleans up at the rest stop
碰巧遇上Nancy Campbell
And then just happens to stumble onto Nancy Campbell.
他短時間內連續犯案
So he didn't wait a minute between victims
還在小孩面前作案
And he left the daughter as a witness.
他為何這麼做
Hey. What's going on with him?
這正是我們要查的
That's what we need to find out.
好
Ok.
最新死者比其他死者都年輕
Latest victim is younger than the others.
也被擺了姿勢嗎
Was she posed as well?
對
Yeah.
Nancy被綁上了新聞
Nancy Campbell's abduction hit the news.
希望嫌犯沒看見
Let's hope he doesn't see it.
他可能因此受驚而加快謀害拋屍
He could panic and then he'll dump her faster than the last one.
他為何拋屍不到一小時就再次犯案
Why has he dumped one victim and taken another within the hour?
有什麼發現  Garcia
What have you got   Garcia?
血腥忙碌的卡車司機
A bloody and busy trucker.
我查了公路連環殺手數據庫
I have been on the hsk myself.
查出四個相關死者
I've connected 4 more victims to this guy.
現在把名字發給你們
I'm sending their names to you now.
加起來有十個人
Brings his count to 10.
把Garcia確認的
We need to get photos of
死者照片貼到板上
the victims garcia identified up on the board.
只要弄清他為何選這些女子
If we figure out why he's choosing these women
就能找到他
We find him.
求求你
please!
求你放了我  我沒法呼吸了
Please   let me out! I can't breathe!
噓
Shh.
你為什麼這麼做
Why are you doing this?
閉嘴就不關燈
Keep quiet and the light stays on.
你想幹什麼
What--what do you want?
你要什麼
What do you want?
你
You.
不  求求你
No...Please...
求求你
Please...
這些是什麼
What's all this?
還有四名死者
There are 4 more victims?
他犯案期比我們想的早幾個月
He started killing months before we thought.
首位死者是Erika Joy
His first victim was Erika Joy
來自南加州  萊剋星頓
From lexington   south carolina.
在卡車加油站失蹤
She disappeared from a truck stop.
從事什麼職業
What did she do for a living?
根據罪檔記錄  什麼都有可能
According to her rap sheet   everyone she could.
這麼說是個蜥蜴
So she's a lot lizard.
在加油站閒逛的妓女的別稱
It's a name they give prostitutes who hang around truck stops.
其他死者呢
What about the others?
女服務員  加油站服務員  女卡車司機
Waitress   gas station attendant   female trucker.
有已婚的嗎
Any of them married?
只有最近被綁的Nancy
Just Nancy Campbell   the latest abductee
她是寡婦
But she's a widow.
她媽媽肯定
Yeah   well   her mom's gonna get
比這些女的
A lot more attention than...
更引人注意
Well   all these other women.
綁架Nancy風險很大
Taking Nancy Campbell was a huge risk.
不符他的作案手法
It doesn't fit his M.O.
其中必有原因
He must have had a reason.
我們有新消息
We just got some new information.
跟我來
Come with me.
抱歉  我稍後回來
Sorry. I'll be back in a minute.
他肯定得從小車旁走過
He had to have walked right by that minivan.
為何不綁架Courtney
Why didn't he take Courtney?
或者她太年輕
Maybe she's too young.
她比母親的年齡更接近死者
She's closer to the victims' ages than her mother.
停車場沒有旁人
That parking lot was deserted.
他大可綁架Courtney  沒人會發現
He could have taken Courtney   nobody would have seen a thing
相反  他從她旁邊走過
But instead   he walks past her--
因為她不是他的人選
Because that's not who he wants.
他監視Nancy
He watched Nancy.
跟蹤她  因為嫌犯要的就是她
He followed her because he wanted her.
以至於要冒險留下Courtney這個目擊者
So much so that he left Courtney as a witness?
是什麼那麼重要
What could be that important?
幾小時前  他有選擇類型
Well   until a few hours ago   he had a type.
其他死者都年輕  單純
The other victims were younger   less sophisticated.
用不了一天
It wouldn't take more than a day
就能知道她們是否適合
To figure out if they're worthy or not.
做什麼
Of what?
做他的伴侶
Being his companion.
這麼說嫌犯完全陷入幻想
Then he's completely delusional.
本來有很多更簡單的方式
There are easier ways to figure that out.
不  對這傢伙而言沒有
No   not for this guy.
他設定時間表迫使他一直停留在路上
He's got a schedule that forces him to stay on the road.
長期孤單一人
He's alone for long stretches.
沒有時間去求愛
He can't devote any real time to courting.
你認為他殺人
You really think he's killing
就因為他寂寞嗎
Because he's lonely?
我不覺得奇怪
It wouldn't surprise me.
煎餅好吃嗎  小公主
How are the pancakes   princess?
沒有你做的好吃
Not as good as yours.
抱歉
Excuse me.
爸爸  你喜歡嗎
Look   daddy. Do you like it?
我看看
Well   now...
真漂亮
Yeah   that's beautiful.
你爸我真的很想你
You know   your daddy really misses you.
能再給我講個故事嗎
Can you tell me another story?
好的
Ok.
然後
So...
孤獨的國王依舊沒有放棄希望
The lonely king had all but given up hope
他堅信自己會找到一位美麗的王后
Of ever finding the beautiful queen.
一瞬之間
When all of a sudden...
她出現了
She appeared.
這一次與以往不同
Now   this time it was different.
這一次
This time
他知道她就是他的真命天女
He knew she was the one.
這一次
This time...
她是那麼完美
She was perfect.
Courtney
Courtney?
Courtney  是你嗎
Courtney   is that you?
你能別晃來晃去的嗎
Hey   will you stop fooling around.
抱歉  親愛的  該走了
Sorry   sweetie   it's time to go.
一定要走嗎
Do we have to?
該上學了
It's time for school.
給
Here.
買根糖果棒
Why don't you go pick out a candy bar
當作甜點
To put in your lunch.
我的公主  別擔心
Oh   hey   princess   don't worry.
我們很快又會是一家人了
We'll be a family again real soon.
你不能再這麼跟她說了
You've got to stop telling her that.
為什麼  那是事實
Why? It's true.
一切都是老樣子
Nothing's changed.
法官不會讓她跟你一起住的
The judge isn't gonna let her live with you.
我在努力...
I am trying--
她已經被收養了
She's being placed with her adoptive family.
她是我的女兒
She is my daughter.
你們這些人不能就這麼把她帶走
You people can't just take her away.
你們不能這樣  我還有時間
You can't just do that! I have more time.
Hatchett先生  請不要這樣
Mr. Hatchett   please.
我希望你來見她
I wanted you to see her
但顯然這是個錯誤
But clearly that was a mistake.
幾個月前  你就已經知道
You've known for months now
這只是可能
That this was a possibility.
我會成功的
I'm gonna make this work.
在這個下午之前嗎
By this afternoon?
你照顧不了她
You can't take care of her.
你照顧自己都很勉強了
You can barely take care of yourself.
你睡在自己的卡車
You're living in your truck.
天天在路上跑  沒有妻子也沒有房子
You're on the road   and without a wife or a home
你真的做不來
You just-- you can't do it.
你必須要放手
You gotta let her go.
讓她快樂的生活
Let her be happy.
我知道你希望Jody快樂
I know you want that for Jody.
她媽媽也希望她過得好
Her mom would want what's best for her.
我也希望她過得好
I'm what's best for her.
我保證過
Look   I made a promise
我決不會讓她遭遇任何不幸
That I would not let anything happen to her.
她是我的寶貝兒
She is my little girl.
沒有人能像我這樣愛她
No one's gonna love her the way that I can.
為什麼你就是不明白呢
Why can't you understand that?
都收拾好了嗎
You all set?
我愛你  爸爸
I love you   daddy.
我也愛你
I love you   too.
皇后怎麼樣了
What about the queen?
她是要找的人嗎
Is she the one?
我不知道
I don't know.
故事還沒有結束  我的公主
The story's not over yet   princess.
Nancy Campbell已經失蹤超過12個小時
Nancy Campbell's been missing over 12 hours.
如果他在我們封鎖交通之前趕到了40號洲際公路
If he jumped on the I-40 before we got the police blocks out--
他現在可能已經在三個州以外了
He could be 3 states over by now.
我們認為他沒有那個時間
We don't think he has time for that.
他囚禁了這些女人  讓她們待在艾吉伍德
He's courting these women. He needs them in Edgewood.
這埵雀W過800輛卡車
There are over 800 truckers on this list.
要讓Garcia調查所有這些卡車的背景資料
We have to get Garcia to run background on all of them.
他要麼把車停在自己家
He's either parked at his own house
要麼就是躲在不起眼之處
Or he's hiding in plain sight.
我們把已經查過的停車站
Listen   I've already given you a list
名單都已經給你們了
Of all the trucker stops that we've checked in town.
我們要再查一遍
We gonna need to check them again.
我找你找了好久
I've searched for you for a long time.
你知道嗎
Did you know that?
你知道家庭有多重要吧
You know how important family is   don't you?
我知道你懂
See   I knew you would.
你跟其他人不一樣
You're not like the others.
想喝點水嗎
Oh   would you like some water?
不了  謝謝
No   thank you.
這樣可不禮貌
That's not polite.
我在與你分享
I'm sharing with you.
你應該接受
You should accept.
好的  謝謝  真是太好了
Yeah   please. That would be great.
好多了
Much better.
家庭就是一切
You know   family's everything.
有了家庭  你永遠也不會孤單
With family   you're-- you're never alone.
求求你
Please...
如果我們的女兒哭了
If our daughter were crying...
你會怎麼哄她
What would you do to get her to stop?
求求你放我走
Please let me go.
如果我們的女兒哭了
If our daughter were crying
你會怎麼哄她
What would you do to get her to stop?
我不知道
I don't know.
我會給她講個故事
I'd tell her a story.
我會抱著她  我不知道
I would--I'd hold her. I don't know.
你喜歡聽故事
You like stories?
我們的女兒很喜歡聽故事
Our daughter likes stories.
看看你  簡直是一團遭
Look at you. You're a mess.
我可不希望我的公主看到你
I don't want the princess to see you
這副髒樣子
All dirty like that.
我有一個女兒
I have a daughter.
求求你放我走
Please let me go.
求求你
Please!
please!
放我出去
Let me go!
求求你
Please...
求求你放我出去
Please let me go!
放我出去
Let me go!
求求你
Please...
-這樣就行  -謝謝
- That's fine.  - Thanks.
你們來是為了調查那個失蹤的女人嗎
Is this about that missing woman?
你知道些什麼
Do you know anything about it?
就是從新聞上看到的那些
Only what I saw on the news.
我們有理由相信嫌犯
We have reason to believe that our suspect
在過去的24小時內來過你這的維修站
Has been in your facility in the past 24 hours.
這
Here?
你們認為他在這
You think he's here?
我們需要你的幫助
We could really use your help.
我們可以提供入貨清單
Well   we could give you our manifest.
上面記錄了所有的卡車司機和貨物
It logs all the truckers and their loads.
那正是我們需要的
That's exactly what we need.
好了  起來  跟我走
All right   get up. You're coming with me.
我說起來
I said get up!
好  冷靜點
All right. Take it easy!
帥哥有什麼需要我幫忙的
It's your dime   Mr. Amazing.
這埵陵灡尾飢A縮小點範圍
Listen   I might have something to narrow your search.
我們認為他沒有給哪家公司打工
We don't think he drives for a company.
這些日程表都排得很滿
The schedules are way too tight.
過去幾個月  他不斷地
In the past few months   he's had the flexibility
綁架和殺人  肯定沒有時間同時運貨
to hunt and kill   and he couldn't do all that and run loads.
所以你需要我縮減範圍到
So you need me to narrow down
獨立承包人
The independent contractors.
你真是瞭解我
You're reading my mind   red.
我剛剛從本地車廠把所有
I just emailed you the manifest from the local depot
貨車司機的名單發給你了  你能不能
where all the truckers check in. Can you
當然可以
Of course I can.
有76張執照登記在個人名下
76 licenses registered under own authority
我都發給你了
And I just sent them back to you.
你真棒
Woman   you are good.
超乎你的想像
You have no idea.
你手上現在有多少件案子
So   how many of these cases have you worked on?
太多了
Too many.
那又有多少女人活著回來
How many of these women have you gotten back alive?
好  我們把案情重新過一遍
All right   so let's go over this again.
這個嫌犯專找25到30歲的
This offender's preferential
年輕女性下手
Young women mid- to late 20s.
他花很多時間跟蹤她們
He takes his time watching them.
確保周圍沒有目擊者
He makes sure there are no witnesses.
綁架過後12到24小時內殺掉她們
He kills them 12 to 24 hours after abduction.
而現在時間縮短了
Only now that timeframe's getting shorter.
然後他回到艾吉伍德
Then he comes home to Edgewood
因為這堿O他的家鄉  讓他有安全感
Where he's home and he feels safe.
聽著Courney  這個男人
Courtney   listen   this man
從不試圖去掩藏他的受害人
He doesn't try to hide his victims.
所以你覺得她還活著
So you think she's still alive?
我之前對她太無禮了
I was so rude to her.
我只是不想讓我對她說的最後一句話是
I just don't want the last thing I said to her to have been...
如果他傷害了她
If he had hurt her
我們現在應該已經找到她了
We would have found her already.
那他到底想把她怎麼樣
So what's he doing to her?
沒有強暴的跡象
There's no rape involved.
所以他只是想找個伴
So is it companionship he's after?
好像中世紀的騎士一樣
There might be an almost chivalrous aspect to this.
你怎麼知道
How do you figure?
卡車司機對自己的生活有種浪漫的幻想
Truckers have a romanticized image of themselves
實際上  當全部的生活
And in fact all lifestyles
都是圍繞寬廣的公路展開時  就會這樣
revolving around the open road do.
比如說地獄天使
The hell's angels   for instance
他們把綁架的女人當成自己的女朋友
They refer to their women as their old ladies
但事實上  他們不願保護任何人
But in fact   there's no one they'd rather protect or die for.
他們對待女人的方式
Their treatment of women
在亞瑟王的時代倒是挺合適
wouldn't be out of place in king arthur's court.
並且孤獨感會增進他們的幻想
And their sense of isolation would amp up their fantasy.
所以他是想找個老婆
So he's looking for a wife.
先從容易的目標下手
He starts out with easy targets
然後慢慢發展到
Then he moves on to women
符合他們幻想的對象
Who could actually fill the role.
親切  善良  熱心的
Sweet   outgoing   warm.
對你過多注意的調酒師
The bartender who takes extra care of you
搭便車的健談女人
The chatty hitchhiker.
但是一天之後
But over the course of the day
她們沒有通過測試  激怒了嫌犯
They fail the test. This infuriates him
所以嫌犯掐死她們然後棄屍
And he strangles them and dumps them.
如果這樣  那他為什麼要找Nancy Campbell
Ok   so why take Nancy Campbell?
她和其他的受害人的特徵相反
She's the opposite of all the other victims he's taken.
沒錯  年紀比較大  還有孩子
It's true. She's older. She already has a kid.
也許正因如此  所以她還活著
Maybe that's why she's still alive.
或許他並不是想找一個伴
What if he's not looking for a companion?
而是一個母親
What if he's looking for a mother?
如果他有個孩子
If he's got a kid of his own
那就知道他一直回來艾吉伍德的原因了
That would explain what keeps him coming back to edgewood.
也能解釋他為什麼不要Courtney
It would explain why he walks past Courtney
而對Nancy下手
To get to Nancy.
他知道她是位母親
Just by watching he knows she's a mother.
所以她能夠通過他的測試
She's already qualified to pass any test.
Garcia
Garcia.
長官
Sir.
我需要你縮小個體車主的範圍
I want you to narrow down the own authority trucker list
看看有誰最近剛離婚
And tell me which ones have been through a divorce recently
或者捲進監護權的官司
Or a custody battle.
監護權官司是個壓力源
Custody fight would be a stressor.
把你搜尋的時間定在第一個受害人之前
Limit your searches to months prior to the first murder.
明白了  謝謝
Got it. Thanks.
出什麼事了
What's going on?
等我一下
Just hold on a second.
等等  怎麼了
Wait   what's going on?
在40號洲際公路找到一具屍體
They found a body off the I-40.
沒有確定身份
No identification.
我媽死了嗎
Is she dead?
我們還不知道
We don't know.
什麼叫你們不知道
What do you mean you don't know?
警察找到了一具屍體
The police found a body
但不確定是不是你母親
and they aren't sure if it's your mother.
我想去看看
I want to go.
我覺得我們應該在這媯
I think we should wait here.
如果是她的話  我想親眼看看
I need to see if it's her.
Courtney  拜託  我和Reid博士會在這堻郁A
Courtney   please   Dr.Reid and I are going to stay here with you
一旦有消息  我們馬上就通知你
and as soon as we know anything   we will tell you.
可以嗎
Ok?
我要給Emily打電話
I'll call Emily.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
好  謝謝
Ok   thanks.
那人不是你母親
It's not your mother.
寶貝  說吧
Hey   baby girl   talk to me.
76個獨立貨車司機堶
Of your 76 independent truckers
有28人被捲進監護權的官司
I have 28 who are currently involved in custody cases.
有多少還沒有宣判
How many of those cases are still open?
有8人
Uh   8 pending.
看來貨車司機不是個增進感情的工作
Not the most relationship friendly job   trucking.
查查那些因為母親死亡的案子
Look for instances where the mother died.
這樣的人不會把孩子從母親身邊搶走的
A guy like this wouldn't tear a child away from his own mother.
Caroline Hatchett在一場火災中身亡了
Caroline Hatchett died in a house fire
留下了7歲的女兒Jody
Leaving behind a 7-year-old daughter Jody
和丈夫Wade Hatchett
And a husband Wade Hatchett.
Wade失去了房子  妻子
Wade lost his home   his wife
還有女兒的監護權
And custody of his daughter
因為法庭認定他無法撫養她
When the courts deemed him unfit.
他還在上訴中
He's still contesting the case.
為什麼認為他無法撫養女兒
Why was he deemed unfit?
工作使得他常常一走就是幾個禮拜
Double whammy--job kept him away for weeks at a time
而且沒有其他親戚可以幫他帶女兒
And he didn't have any other family to help him watch the girl.
看起來他竭盡所能想要照顧她
Looks like he bent over backwards trying to make it work
但是她在學校缺席了太多堂課
But she missed a lot of school
所以判他忽視未成年人
And he was charged with neglect of a minor.
找到他的地址了嗎
You have an address?
只有一個用了一年多的信箱
Just a P.O. Box for over a year.
他女兒呢
What about the daughter?
Jody現在被別人撫養
Jody currently resides in foster care.
我現在把文件發給你
I'm sending you the file now.
如果這是同一個不明嫌犯所為
If this is the same unsub
他甚至沒有為她擺好姿勢
He didn't bother to pose her this time.
這次比過去殘忍多了
This is much more brutal.
感覺起來像是在報復
It feels personal.
她叫Lynn Clemons
Her name is Lynn Clemons.
上面100碼的地方找到她的錢包
Deputies found her wallet about 100 yards up.
肯定是棄屍的時候調出來了
Must have spilled out when he dumped her.
Garcia  幫我查出有關
Garcia   we need everything that you have
Lynn Clemons的一切
on a Lynn Clemons.
Lynn Clemons  她是
Lynn Clemons? She's the...
她是Jody的養父母
Foster parent of Jody Hatchett.
我才剛告訴其他人
I was just telling the others
她的父親是個失去監護權的貨車司機
Her father is a trucker who lost custody
他失去了監護權
When his wife died.
而Jody就要被收養
Jody's in the process of being adopted.
他快沒時間了
He ran out of time.
派人去他家了嗎
Is the team on their way to his house?
沒有  他只有個郵政信箱
No   he only has a P.O. Box.
他殺了孩子的養母
He killed the foster parent.
肯定要去找他女兒
He's going after his daughter.
Garcia  Jody Hatchett現在哪
Garcia   where's Jody Hatchett right now?
等一下
Wait!
嗨  Jody
Hey   Jody.
你是誰
Who are you?
我是Emily
I'm Emily.
Clemons太太呢
Where's Mrs. Clemons?
我們進去再說好嗎
Well   I'll tell you inside   ok?
沒事的  來吧
It's ok. Come on.
Jody
Jody.
怎麼回事
What's going on?
我們在協助警方  尋找你的父親
We're helping the police   and we're trying to find your dad.
你知道他在哪兒嗎
Do you know where he is?
不知道
No.
Hotch  有輛卡車開過來了
Hotch   truck's coming up the road right now.
Jody  我們能去你房間玩嗎
Hey   Jody   can we go play in your room?
這邊
It's right here.
好
Ok.
好了
All right.
快起來
Get up.
有人進了前駕駛室
Somebody's moving toward the front of the cab.
那是Nancy Campbell
All right   it's Nancy Campbell.
他在她身後  用槍指著她
He's behind her and he's got his gun on her.
Morgan  能射中他嗎
Morgan   do you have a shot?
不行
Negative. Negative.
他把她作為擋箭牌
He's using her as a shield.
為了找回他女兒  他可能會殺了Nancy
Hotch   he might kill Nancy to get to Jody.
這些都是你畫的嗎
Did you paint all of these yourself?
感覺像是  她們在睡覺嗎
It looks like they're... Sleeping?
國王替她們蓋好被子  就像我爸爸那樣
Yeah. The king tucks them in   just like my daddy does for me.
這個是你媽媽嗎
Is this your mom here   this one?
不  這是王后
No. That's the queen.
誰是王后
Who's that?
國王想帶她回城堡
She's the one that the king tried to take home
但沒能成功
to the castle   but she didn't make it.
她怎麼了
What happened her?
她的馬車壞了
Her carriage broke down
為了救公主  國王不得不留下她
And he had to leave her behind to save the princess.
有很多王后啊
There's a lot of queens here.
長得都不一樣
They all look different.
是啊
They are.
這個王后怎麼樣了
What happened to this one here?
她太髒了
She was dirty.
國王說
The king said   "How do you expect
她連自己都照顧不好
"To give my daughter a bath
又怎麼來照顧公主呢
If you can't even take one yourself?"
這故事我很喜歡
I like that story.
這些故事都是你自己編的嗎
Do you make up all these stories?
不是  是我爸爸說給我聽的
No. My daddy does.
我喜歡把它們畫出來
I like painting them.
這個故事還沒結束吧
Well   this story isn't over yet   is it?
爸爸也這麼說
That's what my dad said.
是嗎
He did?
我們今天一起吃烤薄煎餅時
Today we were eating pancakes
他說她很完美
And he said she was perfect.
你想見見王后嗎
Hey   would you like to meet a queen?
當然
Yeah.
是嗎
Yeah?
Jody在哪兒
Where's Jody?
我找不到她  他們把她怎麼樣了
I don't see her. What did they do with her?
Jody多大了
How old is Jody?
她會喜歡我嗎
Do you think she'll like me?
爸爸  你在嗎
Daddy? Daddy   are you there?
嗨  寶貝兒
Hi   baby.
你得把故事說完
You need to tell me the rest of the story.
孤獨的國王和王后正在城堡
Well   the lonely king and the queen are at the castle.
什麼時候來接公主呢
To pick up the princess?
現在不行  有守衛在
No   the guards are in the way.
讓王后和他們談談吧
Will you let the queen talk to them?
他們不會聽
They won't listen.
但我想見她
But I want to see her.
你能讓她過來抱抱我嗎
Will you let her go so she can hold me?
你也說她很完美
You said that she's perfect
她就是終生的伴侶
That she's the one.
她會和我一起生活在大城堡
She wants to live in a big castle with me.
我要看看你
I need to see you.
好
Ok.
嗨  爸爸
Hi   daddy!
嗨  小公主
Hi   princess.
她真美  爸爸
She's so pretty   daddy!
快去
Go   go.
國王再也不會孤單一人了
Now the king won't be lonely anymore.
是啊
No.
他們會幸福快樂地生活在一起
And they're gonna live happily ever after.
你也一起來吧  爸爸
Why aren't you coming   too   daddy?
你做得很棒  Jody
You did a great job   Jody.
你要去更好的地方嗎
Are you going to the better place?
什麼
What?
是啊  我們會在那堿蛪|  小公主
Yeah. We're both going to a better place   princess.
閉上你的小眼睛  寶貝兒
Close your little eyes   sweet pea.
Hatchett
Hatchett!
轉過身來
Turn around.
克奡策咱情P拉什說道[著名美國史學家]
Christopher Lasch said
現實生活鐵石心腸  唯有家庭宛如天堂
"Family is a haven in a heartless world."
你在看什麼
What you reading?
公路連環殺手數據庫
The HSK database.
此時此刻  這其中可能有半打人
Do you know there's probably half a dozen serial killers
正在駕車四處殺人
driving around right now?
是什麼讓你耿耿於懷
What's really bothering you?
Jody失去了母親
Jody lost her mom
又失去了父親
and then her dad
現在肯定沒人敢領養她了
And the couple that was gonna adopt her backed out.
新聞堥麭B都是
It's all over the news.
我只是覺得
It's just...
這不公平
It's just not fair.
她的阿姨得知此事
Her aunt saw the story.
她站了出來
She came forward.
過去幾年她和Jody的媽媽
She'd lost touch with Jody's mom
失去了聯繫  現在是她唯一在世的親屬
over the past few years   but she's her only living relative
她願意撫養Jody
And she wants to raise Jody.
是嗎
Really?
要知道  Prentiss
You know   Prentiss
我一想起每天經歷的這些
When I think about the things we see on a daily basis
所有的邪惡面
All the bad
而我依然驚嘆於善的力量
I'm still amazed at all the good.
是啊  但是
Yeah   but...
你覺得善與惡的勢力均衡嗎
Do you think it evens out?
但願如此
I'd like to think it does.